

Rakesh Kasarla

Python | Data Scientist | ML Engineer

- 9491357016
- 🔀 Hyderbad, India
- **Github**
- Portfolio

SKILLS

Programming skills:

Python, C Language, PL/SQL, Shell Script

Databases:

• MySQL, SQL Server, Oracle Server, Mango dB

Machine Learning Algorithms:

- **Supervised ml algorithms**:
 - Linear regression
 - o logistic regression
 - o support vector machine
 - o decision tree
 - o random forest
 - o ada boosting
 - gradient boosting
 - XGBoost
 - o KNN
 - o naive Bayes

Unsupervised ml algorithms:

- K-means clustering
- hierarchical clustering
- o DBSCAN

SUMMARY

1.5 years of IT experience from TCS and 4 months of internship as a ML Engineer in ineuron.io, looking for transition to the Data Scientist Role. With interest in analyzing raw data and statistics, brings excellent communication abilities with hands-on experience in building machine learning models with deployment.

EXPERIENCE

Oracle-DBA, TCS

Oracle Database Administrator

May2021-Present

- working with database software to find ways to store, organize and manage data.
- Working on troubleshooting and keeping databases up to date.
- Helping with database design and development and managing database access.
- Designing maintenance procedures and putting them into operation.

Machine Learning Intern, ineuron.ai

Credit Card Default Prediction

June2021-Aug2022

- The main objective of this project is to predict the Credit Card defaulters based on their previous transaction's behaviors.
- Data set was taken from Kaggle and having more than 30000 records.
- Used different machine learning algorithms for training and finally random forest with hyperparameter tunning model gave highest accuracy with 83% and 80% of precision.
- I have also used k-means clustering algorithm to reduce the error.
- Deployed model as CI/CD pipeline by using Heroku with github actions.
- Code Link: Click here
- **Internship Experience Letter**

PROJECTS

IPL First Innings Score Prediction

June2021

- The main objective of this project is to predict score of ipl team based on that team previous 5 overs in the same match.
- This is a regression problem so I have used Linear regression model for training with accuracy of 80%.
- I have used Linear regression algo for model training and flask for api and used Heroku for deployment.
- For more details, please visit my Github code repo: Click Here

Frameworks:

• Flask , Django and tkinter.

Web Development:

HTML, CSS and JavaScript

MLops:

Circle CI, Mlflow, Docker and github actions

Cloud Platforms:

AWS, Heroku and Azure (Basics)

Python Libraries:

- NumPy,
- Pandas
- Matplotlib,Seaborn.Plotly
- Scikit-learn
- TensorFlow
- Pickle
- Xgboost
- Beautiful Soup, Requests
- Flask, Django

TOOLS

- PyCharm
- Anaconda
- Jupiter notebook
- vs code
- git and github
- google colab

INTERESTS

- Coding
- Data science
- Artificial intelligence
- Playing with Data
- Playing Video Games

Diabetics Predication

May-2022

April-2022

• The main objective of this project is to predict weather a woman having diabetics or not based on given some parameters.

- This is classification problem so I have trained my data with many machine learning algorithms finally Random Forest Classifier has given highest accuracy and recall value i.e. mor than 80%.
- For more details, please visit my Github code repo: Click Here

House Prices Prediction (Kaggle Competition)

- The main objective of this project is to predict the sales price for each house. For each Id in the test set, you must predict the value of the Sale Price variable.
- It is a Advanced Problem of Regression which requires advanced techniques of feature engineering, feature selection and extraction, modeling, model evaluation, and Statistics.
- advanced techniques of feature engineering, feature selection and extraction, modeling, model evaluation, and Statistics.
- my most recent submission Root-Mean-Squared-Error (REMS) scored 0.12424 and got 573 ranks in Leader board

Certifications

- Having Python certification from Naresh it technologies.
- Did Machine Learning certification from Udemy & ineuron
- SQL and HTML basics certification from geeksforgeeks.
- Secured 1573 rank in House price Kaggle competition Leader board.

Education

Tudi ram reddy institute of technology & sciences(TRRIT) , Nalgonda

Computer Science Engineering

2016-2020

Sri Balaji Junior College, Hanamkonda

MPC 2014-2016

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Date of birth: 03-November-1997

Hobbies: Reading books & playing cricket.

Languages: English & Telugu & Hindi